Finding Aid for Carl Addison Leech papers, 1928-1940
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Carl Addison Leech papers 1928-1940
Leech, Carl Addison.
2 linear feet
851659 Aa 2
Historian of Michigan’s lumber industry; correspondence and research materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Carl A. Leech (donor no. 917 ) and came to the library beginning in 1939.
The collection is open to research.
Carl A. Leech was a resident of Detroit, Michigan and a writer of historical articles on the history of lumbering, Michigan lumbering communities, and the careers of individuals associated with lumbering in Michigan.
The collection consists of three series: Correspondence; Research materials; and Miscellaneous. The correspondence dates from 1928 to 1940 and includes letters received in response to various queries. The research materials include notes relating to his interest in Michigan lumbering, the development of lumbering within such cities as Deward, Roscommon, Saginaw, Meredith, Seney, and Muskegon. One of Leech's principal research interest was the life and career of "Silver Jack" John Driscoll.
Subjects:
Deward (Mich.); Driscoll, John.; Harcourt, Bert.; Logging--Michigan.; Lumbering--Michigan.; Meredith (Mich.); Muskegon (Mich.); Roscommon (Mich.); Saginaw (Mich.); Seney (Mich.)
- Correspondence
  - Undated and 1928-1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933 (Box 1)
  - 1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 1)
- Research materials
  - Michigan prisons (Box 1)
  - Roscommon (Box 1)
  - Local color, songs and ballads, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Saginaw, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Meredith, Mich. (Box 1)
  - "Silver Jack" John Driscoll
    - General, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Correspondence with Bert Harcourt regarding Driscoll and other topiccs, 1938-1940 (Box 1)
    - Reminiscence of Bert Harcourt concerning "Silver Jack" Driscoll, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Seney, Mich. (Box 1)
  - Lumbering in Michigan, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Muskegon (Box 1)
  - Land grabbing and fraud in timber acquisition, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Notes on events in various years, 3 folders (Box 1)
- Articles written and miscellaneous
  - Article on "Paul Bunyan's Land and the First Sawmills of Michigan" (Box 1)
  - Article on "Deward-the Model of Michigan's Old Lumbering Towns" (Box 1)
  - List of photographs in the Leech collection (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 26 volumes (Box 2)